what's up guys here are five different
delt exercises that I think you should
consider adding into your program now
I've been lifting weights for 33 years
right I started when I was 15 I'm 48 I
didn't think it was possible to add size
to my delts but I have in the past year
and a lot of the growth I attribute to
the exercises I'm about to show you but
I do want to point out 10 years ago if I
wanted my delts to grow I would hit
military press harder I'd try to use
Progressive overload for shoulder press
upright rows I try to focus on the big
movements you know close grip bench rows
military upright rows and this past year
I didn't do any of that I've not done
much overhead press at all I have not
done nearly as many rows but what I have
done is trained delts every third or
fourth day with more volume but I didn't
go for PRS I wasn't trying to hit you
know Progressive overload with lateral
raises all the time I did that in the
past with dumbbells I had worked my way
up to 40 lb dumbbells for 20 rep
50 Pounders for 10 with a lot of heaving
a lot of body English I didn't use as
much dumbbells this year I used cables I
did a lot of length in partials I'd do
at least one front delt one side delt
and one rear delt movement then I'd add
in you know a band finisher or like the
seated lad raid machine I do about 10
total sets and call it a day but I was
doing two delt days a week so and what I
will tell you is doing a lot of these
lengthen partials and the cable reared
out rows the band stuff I'm about to
show you it doesn't beat you up much
you're not fatigued from it so if you
want to grow your delts do what I've
done try these exercises see if you like
them see if they work for you but also
try to train your delts twice a week
with around 8 to 12 steps because you do
get front delt volume with every
compound upper body press you do you get
rear delt stimulus from every compound
upper body pull you do so you don't want
to go too crazy with the volume but you
also want to choose joint friendly
movement if I was just doing a ton of
lateral raises you know they might
irritate me but by mixing it up
sometimes doing dumbbells some times
cables sometimes bands sometimes length
and partials you can tolerate more and
it just distributes The Joint stress so
you don't get injuries you don't get any
nagging pain and the end result is just
pure delt growth so give these a try I
think you're going to like
them all right first up we have the
cable lengthened front Rays so um
ideally with the the delt fibers you you
wouldn't just be doing pure front Rays
you might incorporate like some angular
Motion in there to match the fibers you
also want the resistance to be
perpendicular at the bottom so ideally
you'd max out torque and stretch at the
bottom so when you're in a deep stretch
you also want torque to be maximized in
that position so that's why I set this
up
accordingly I
got all
right
so I'm not not going to lean forward I'm
going to lean up because from here I
want there to be a lot of torque in this
starting position and I want to go back
into a deep stretch
so from here come up and in
interestingly you'll feel this in the
biceps as well
because it is under a lot of stretch
tension throughout the
movement so all I've done is the cable
lengthen front Rays you can see they're
pumped but
my middle and rear delts are not pumped
so same
but front
delts pumped
up all right now this is a cable side
delt length and partial so you can do it
actually behind the back like this and
you can also do it in front I kind of
like doing it in front more this is my
preferred but I do recommend you try
both ways but you don't come up all the
way and you want this roughly
perpendicular
but you're not straight to the side
you're not like this you're actually
facing forward a little bit okay so kind
of comes across you and then it's just
from here
so yeah just from that set see my side
jts getting
pumped now you see the middle JS popping
out front jts were already popping out
now you see the middle delts so this is
set up at roughly hip
height and again you're not going
straight out to the side this way
you're turning a little bit so step
forward take the tension off and from
here so you can feel tension stretching
you right here from the get-go you can
go lighter and do a full range of motion
but I like going heavier
[Music]
so roughly hip height or like roughly
hand height which is going to be in the
stretch so it's like you see here you
want this cable pretty horizontal right
here if you're doing it right turn
so now I just did the side delt exercise
the cable side delt length and partial
and now you can
see my middle delts more pumped right
they're popping out
more still my rear delts not
pumped
but side delts are
Fuller all right and now we have the
cable rear delt row now I've been doing
this a lot over the past year this has
been my number one main rear delt
movement and they have grown but you're
going to be amazed at how much these
pump up my rear delts like right now not
pumped after I do a set of these they
look pregnant it looks like I have
Synthol pumped into them it's insane and
if an exercise works you in the
lengthened position and gives you a pump
it's got to be good for muscle growth
these stretch the rear delts but you're
just doing a row so you can go heavier
you're not coming straight out you're
doing a row it's amazing I really hope
that many of you can try this exercise
out because it's truly been I hate the
term game Cher but this has really been
beneficial for me over the past year I
also hate training delts one arm at a
time I hate all single arm movements
single leg movements I just like
bilateral this lets me hit the rear
delts at the same time here it
goes so full stretch
[Music]
so one
set yeah start to see that rear Del
pump just from one
set so I do three sets it's going to be
even more pronounced
just finished the cable rear del
row are they more
pumped from behind are they popping out
obviously I can't see all I know is that
this
exercise has single-handedly added Mass
to my rear delts and I'm 48 years old
I've been lifting since I was 15 after
33 years of training if you can still
see gains you got to be doing something
right all right now we've got the banded
lat Rays you need two monster mini bands
these are the 41in bands that are
usually red or pink you Loop one around
this a hack squat machine but you're
going to have something similar at your
gym one around the other
Peg now from here I'm going to crisp
cross I'm going to hook
these
right around the wrist okay now from
here I'm going to lean back just
slightly what I want to do is create the
most tension at the top so everything's
about the stretch these days well what
about the lockout position what about
the short muscle position so from here
bend the elbows
[Music]
that Burns Burns good but these I feel
like when you have an exercise that
doesn't work you as much in the stretch
it works you in the
squeeze it does not create muscle damage
it doesn't create as much fatigue so
it's just penalty-free volume you can
throw this in couple sets at the end of
your workout and it's not going to
fatigue you you it's just icing on the
cake in my opinion an added benefit you
can see my traps can get a pump from
these
two um I don't even do shrugs anymore my
traps stay pretty big from deadlifts and
different delt raises what I like about
this is you can kind of back up and move
forward to make it easier lighter you
can make it kind of like a
natural drop set kind of so can start
out
further these are the three stances I
recommend when doing the banded lateral
raise
and this one I've been doing for I think
maybe 16 years this I call the band face
pull apart or the band face pull pull
apart you're kind of combining a face
pull and a pull
apart so just Loop it through anything
sturdy and then you're going to walk
back now you got to sometimes you're
going to take too wide of a grip you got
to work with it it's got to be just the
right grip
with and I've gotten really strong at
these and what you're going to do is you
don't just do a face pull you're also
going to pull apart as you do it so it
looks like this
now I measured the EMG activity of this
exercise and I was amazed at how high it
got the rear delts but also the side
delts and it didn't make sense to me at
the time this was like
2010 and then as I thought about it you
can see from the rear view at the
lockout you are working the middle delts
very hard as well well so I never start
the workout out with these These are
always a finisher but I do think it's
wise to toss these band exercise in from
time to time because I don't think they
fatigue you much they don't create any
muscle damage it can only help as long
as you don't overdo it on volume and
you're trying to train delts every day
which no one does then it can only help